We've been able to run webpack,
我们已经能够运行 webpack
to create a dist folder,
创建一个 dist 文件夹
so now let's talk a little bit more about what that dist folder is and what it's doing.
现在深入了解一下 dist 文件夹及其作用
Dist stands for distribution and it sits next to
dist 是 distribution 的缩写 表示分发
our source folder and the two
与源文件夹 (src) 并列
of them play a really important point in front-end development.
这两个文件夹在前端开发中扮演着非常重要的角色
The source folder is all the folders that you create,
源文件夹中包括你创建的所有文件夹
it's all of the asset files that you write,
是你编写的所有资源文件
and all of those files that you're going to edit.
以及你需要编辑的所有文件
The distribution folder, is for giving out to all of the web pages as there run,
分发文件夹 是负责网页运行时的分发
so your website that's running for a client or for a user on the browser,
因此客户或浏览器的用户正在运行的网站
is going to reference the distribution file and not the source file.
引用的是分发文件而不是源文件
That's a really big concept that I want you to walk away with and be really solid
这是一个非常重要的概念 希望你能牢牢掌握
on because they think it's something that junior devs often struggle with,
因为这是初级开发者经常困惑的地方
it's this idea that when you go to edit a file for your company, where do you edit it,
当你为公司编写代码时究竟要编辑哪个文件 就是基于这个概念
there's going to be two versions of the same file or if you go to edit a style,
同一文件有两个版本 或者说如果你要编辑样式
that style is going to show up in multiple style sheets but
该样式出现在多个样式表中
which one do you edit and what's the difference between the two?
你应该编辑哪一个? 两者有什么区别?
The distribution folder, is going to have every style that you've written inside of it,
分发文件夹里有你编写的所有样式
and also the source file is going to have
源文件夹同样也包含你在源文件中编写的所有样式
So when you go to edit a file and you want that change to be seen on the web page,
因此 当你要编辑文件并希望在网页上看到变化时
you might go to the distribution file and you
你可能会选择分发文件
would change the style that you need to edit,
修改需要编辑的样式
so let's say that you are editing the background color of a button and that button,
假设你要编辑按钮的背景色
needs to be blue but it's red,
按钮需要是蓝色 但现在是红色
well, you might go to the distribution file and you would change the style in
那么 你可能会去分发文件夹
your main.css or your bundle.css file,
修改 main.css 或 bundle.css 中的样式
and you would see the button immediately change from red to blue,
你会看到按钮立即从红色变为蓝色
which is perfect and that's what you wanted and so
貌似很完美 因为这正是你想要的结果
you would think that you had done the task.
你认为自己已经完成了任务
But the problem is that you didn't really change the file, what happens is,
但问题是你并没有真正改变文件
all of your source files are run through a build tool and
实际上 所有源文件都会通过构建工具运行
the distribution file is generated by that built tool from the styles that are in source.
分发文件是由构建工具从源文件中的样式生成的
So you might change the distribution file but it's going to
因此 你虽然可以修改分发文件
get overwritten every time that you rebuild those source files.
但是每次重新构建这些源文件后 分发文件又会被重写
So you might make a change to the source file,
因此 你应该修改源文件
and you would see nothing happened on the web page yet.
虽然修改后不能立即在网页上看到任何变化
In fact, once you build those styles,
但实际上 一旦对这些样式进行构建
run them through your build tool,
通过构建工具运行
then you will actually generate that new distribution file and your styles will be there.
就将生成新的分发文件 修改的样式也在其中
So I think it's a thing that took me a
所以 虽然这个概念
long time to get but it's a really important thing to get,
需要花费很长时间理解 但真的非常重要
that if you go to change the built file,
如果你更改构建生成的文件
you'll see the change immediately but it won't be permanent and
会立即看到更改 但这不持久
if you want to change that style permanently,
而如果你想永久更改样式
then you need to change the source files and rebuild in order
需要更改源文件并重新构建
to get those files or get those styles into the built folder.
将这些文件或样式输出到构建文件夹中
The distribution file, is exactly what that is for,
分发文件正是用于此目的
so here we created a new disk folder and inside of it is the
所以我们在这里创建了一个新的 dist 文件夹 里面有一个
main.js and the JavaScript that we put into our index.js file,
main.js 其中包含 index.js 文件中的 JavaScript
shows up here just fine,
看起来很好
but there are some problems with this, first off,
但还有一些问题 首先
this main.js file that we've created,
我们创建的这个 main.js 文件
isn't being used anywhere,
没有在任何地方用到
it's just sitting there,
仅仅是放在那
it has no connection whatsoever to our view.
没有和我们的视图建立任何连接
So if we go to look at our view folder in our index.html file,
如果去看一下 view 文件夹中的 index.html
here we see that the assets that we're bringing in,
可以看到引入的资源
are the styles and JavaScript files that we've
是我们创建的样式和 JavaScript 文件
created and they're the direct reference to those files in source,
直接引用了源文件夹中的文件
but that's not what we need anymore.
但这并不是我们所需要的
Now, we actually need to reference the dist folder for all of those,
现在 我们实际上需要引用的是 dist 文件夹下的文件
so I'm going to "Add" a new reference to the dist main.js file,
所以我要添加一个新的引用到 dist 文件夹下的 main.js 文件
and what's going to be really cool about that,
真正有趣的是
is that we actually don't even need these anymore,
我们实际上不再需要下面这些引用了
we can just get rid of all of these and just stick with the reference to dist.
可以删除这些 只保留对 dist 的引用
Now, to be honest we're actually going to get rid
说实话 我们稍后实际上也要删除
of this hard-coded reference to dist in just a little while,
对 dist 的硬编码引用
but just so that you can get a hold of the concept,
现在这样做只是为了让你理解这个概念
that we no longer need references to all the source files
我们不再需要引用所有源文件
because they are all being generated into these distributed files.
因为它们最终都将生成分发文件
Our HTML file, is now referencing the correct distribution file,
HTML 文件现在引用了正确的分发文件
but we still have a problem with this code that we need to address and that issue is
但这个代码依然有问题要解决
that our index.js file is not taking in any of the JavaScript that we've already built.
index.js 文件没有使用我们已经创建的任何 JavaScript
In fact, it has no connection whatsoever to all of the files that are in our js folder,
实际上 它与 js 文件夹中的所有文件都没有任何联系
so if we take a look at our JavaScript's,
如果看一下我们的 JavaScript
we have two files here that we need to bring into the index.js file.
这里有两个文件需要引入到 index.js 文件中
Now, if you're just reaching for a tool you might want to just say like,
现在 如果你想要的只是一个工具 你可能想说
"Oh I want to require this file."
我想获取 (require) 这个文件
But the problem is that,
但问题是
this is client side,
这是在客户端
we're on a browser we don't have require,
使用的是浏览器 没有 require 模块
we can't just get things from wherever we want,
无法随意从想要的地方拿到东西
so how do we actually bring these files
那么 在不将所有文件写到同一个文件的前提下
in without just throwing them all in the same file.
如何引入这些文件呢?
Well, to do this,
要做到这一点
a common thing that developers will choose to do is to add a tool called Babel.
开发者通常会选择添加一个名为 Babel 的工具
Babel is a specialized tool that translates one version of JavaScript to
Babel 是一个专用工具 能将 JavaScript 的一个版本转换为另一个版本
another and it will allow us to use newer versions of JavaScript and the syntax for them,
使我们可以使用更新版本的 Javascript 及其语法
even though the browser doesn't run those natively.
即使浏览器还没有提供支持
So for instance, it will allow us to run ES6,
例如 即使浏览器还不能识别 ES6
when the browser doesn't know what ES6 is,
我们也可以借助它来运行 ES6
because Babel is going to translate all of that newer syntax,
因为 Babel 会将所有新语法翻译成
into a syntax that the browser can understand.
浏览器可以识别的语法
In the end, what that will allow us to do,
最终 这将使我们能够
is run import statements, ES6 import statements,
在 index.js 文件中运行 ES6 的 import 语句
in order to bring in the other JavaScript files that we've written.
来引入我们编写的其他 JavaScript 文件
It might seem a little bit silly,
这看起来有点傻
that in order to configure webpack we have to also configure and install Babel,
为了配置 webpack 我们还必须配置和安装 Babel
but that's really just the way that all of these configurations go,
但这确实就是这些配置的工作方式
you install multiple tools at
为了到达自己想要的效果
the same time in order to get the setup exactly the way you want it.
你需要同时安装多个工具
So in the next step,
所以 下一步
we're going to install Babel,
我们来安装 Babel
so as we get ready to install Babel all of the commands that you need to run,
准备安装 Babel 时 需要运行的所有命令
are going to be part of the course materials so that you don't have to memorize them,
可以在教室页面的内容中找到 你不用记住
no one expects you to memorize them.
没人期望你记住
So to get started here,
所以从这里开始
I'm currently just in the root of my project,
我目前位于项目的根目录下
I am on the same level as the package.json file,
与 package.json 文件同一层级
and I'm going to run this command.
运行这个命令
So let's unpack this a little bit,
再展开说一下这个命令
I'm doing an npm install and in npm,
我在执行 npm 安装操作 而在 npm 中
when you add the dash d to a command,
当你在命令中添加 -D 选项
it means that you're installing this to development.
意味着将其安装到开发环境中
This means that all of the packages that we're installing right now,
这意味着现在安装的所有软件包
are not for the production side of our application,
不是用于应用的生产环境
they don't need to be present when we are actually serving our app to users,
当我们实际向用户提供应用服务时 它们不需要出现
instead, these are just going to be available during the development process.
相反 它们仅在开发过程中可用
So we're installing Babel
后面的内容表示 我们要安装 Babel
and some of the presets that Babel needs in order to work with webpack,
以及一些 Babel 与 webpack 设置所需的预设
So I'm going to run that,
运行命令
and while that's running we're going to come back to
在运行的同时 我们回到代码中
our code and set up some of the other things that we need.
做一些需要的其他设置
Babel, much like webpack requires a configuration file,
和 webpack 很像的是 Babel 也需要一个配置文件
so at the same level,
它们在同一层级
at the root level,
根目录
right next to our webpack config js,
在 webpack.config.js 旁边
I'm going to "Add" a new file,
我新建一个新文件
and we're going to call that the babelrc file,
将其命名为 babelrc
and.babelrc, once we've created the babelrc file,
前面加个点 .babelrc 创建 .babelrc 文件之后
we're just going to add a few configurations that will just set the preset for babelrc.
要添加一些配置 用于设置 babelrc 的预设 (preset)
You don't need to think too much about these, in fact,
实际上 你不需要考虑太多
we're not going to go too in depth into Babel at all,
我们不会去深究 Babel
we're going to stay more on the surface,
会更多地停留在表层
for now just know that these are the configurations that you
现在 你只要知道这些配置是为了
need in order to get Babel up and working for ES6,
使 Babel 工作起来 能够使用 ES6
depending on your project and your setup you might need to change other things but
根据你的项目和设置 你可能还需要更改其他内容
Babel has pretty good documentation for
不过 Babel 提供了优秀的文档
helping you figure out what all of those configurations are.
可以帮助你找到需要的配置
So for now, we're just going to use these presets,
对于当前项目来说 我们就使用这些预设
so now, that we have Babel configured and installed,
现在已经配置并安装了 Babel
we can use it to import all of our JavaScript files,
我们可以用它来导入所有的 JavaScript 文件
and now we have access to that really cool ES6 syntax where we can use an import.
现在 我们可以使用非常酷的 ES6 语法 直接用 import 导入
So as an example of an import,
作为一个 import 的示例
I can "Add" a reference to the formHandler function,
我来添加一个对 formHandler 中函数的引用
that's some custom JavaScript that I wrote and
这是一段我写的 JavaScript 代码
the handleSubmit is just what we're going to call it on this side,
handleSubmit 就是我们要调用的函数
and that is going to reference this formHandler function here.
引用自这里的 formHandler 函数
Now, you can see that I've already exported this function preemptively,
可以看到我已经事先导出 (export) 了这个函数
this export is what allows us to import the file here.
这个导出让我们能够在这里导入
Exports and imports can get a little bit confusing but you just have to
导出和导入可能会有些困惑 但是你只需要记住
remember that they're like exporting and importing things to different countries.
它们就像不同国家之间商品出口和进口一样
You can't import something unless it has also already been exported from somewhere else.
除非 "商品" 已经从某个地方导出 否则不能执行导入
So you'll never have any luck importing something if you
所以 你永远无法侥幸导入一个
haven't already exported it from the file where you wrote it.
还没有从编写的文件里导出过的东西
So now, we can use this ES6 import statements in our index.js file.
现在 我们可以在 index.js 文件中使用这个 ES6 的 import 语句
Babel is the thing that allows us to use this ES6,
Babel 就是让我们能够使用 ES6 的工具
it's taking this ES6 syntax and turning it into normal JavaScript for our browser,
它将 ES6 语法转换为适用于我们浏览器的普通 JavaScript
which is really cool, but in order to use Babel,
这真的很酷 但是要使用 Babel
there's one last thing that we need to do and it takes us into our next webpack concept.
还有最后一件事要做 这将带我们进入 webpack 下一个概念的学习
If we come back to our webpack config file,
回到 webpack 配置文件
we're going to add one piece to it and that is a rule, now,
我们要在其中添加一些内容 一条规则 (rules)
these are loaders and JavaScript webpack uses
这些就是加载器 (loader) JavaScript webpack 使用
loaders and plug-ins to achieve the bundling of all of our assets.
加载器和插件 (plugin) 来实现所有资源的打包
This is an example of a loader,
这是一个加载器的示例
and this in particular is the Babel loader.
准确地说是 Babel 加载器
We installed it when we installed all of the tools for Babel,
我们在安装 Babel 工具时就安装了它
but now we're actually going to use it,
但是直到现在才开始使用
and this is the first time that you'll see us using a rule in webpack, and you can see,
这也是你第一次看到我们在 webpack 中使用规则 你可以看到
that it just goes under an array of rules and we actually use regex,
它出现在 rules 数组中 我们使用了正则表达式
to isolate the type of file that we're going to run this loader on.
来关联要运行该加载器的文件类型
So in this case, we're looking for anything that ends in.js.
在这个示例中 我们匹配以 .js 结尾的文件
So when webpack generates the dependency tree,
当 webpack 生成依赖关系树时
it is going to have a whole bunch of
依赖关系树中会有很多不同类型的文件
This is saying that any of those asset files that end in a.js,
这里就是说 任何以 .js 结尾的资源文件
need to be treated or run through this particular loader.
需要通过这个特定的加载器进行处理
Now, a really cool thing about this loader is that,
现在 关于此加载器的一件很酷的设定是
we don't want to run it on all of our node modules,
我们不想让它在 node_modules 中的所有文件上运行
so we can also exclude certain files or certain files
我们可以排除某些特定文件或
in certain directories from being used in this loader.
某些特定目录下的文件使其不被此加载器使用
We'll talk about more loaders in a second,
稍后我们会讨论更多的加载器
but just to get started this is the Babel loader that is going to allow us to
以 Babel 加载器作为开始是因为它可以
use webpack on our JavaScript files.
让我们在 JavaScript 文件上使用 webpack
So if we come over and re-run our build command,
如果我们回过头重新运行构建命令
you'll see that we have the index.js file which is the one that
你会看到有一个 index.js 文件 该文件是
we've had and it's where webpack is starting from our dependency tree, but now,
之前就有的 也是 webpack 构建依赖树开始的地方 但是现在
we also have a new one which is formHandler.js,
还有一个新的 formHandler.js 文件
because that's the file that we just imported,
这是刚才导入的文件
and when we import a file into index.js,
当我们将文件导入 index.js 时
it becomes a dependency that webpack will search through and find,
它就成为 webpack 搜索和查找的依赖项
and if it so happened that handle.submit has another dependency,
这种情况下 如果 handleSubmit 还有另一个依赖项
webpack will go through and find that as well.
webpack 会以同样的方式继续查找
So now, that we have this import statement,
现在 我们加了这个 import 语句
we can go back to the terminal and we can see it run.
可以回到终端看它如何运行
So when we run this,
运行命令后
we'll see that the old import rules,
我们会看到那个旧的规则
we only had a main.js file here,
只有一个 main.js 文件 (口误 应该是指 index.js 文件)
but in our most recent build,
但是在最新的构建中
we have not only the index.js file,
不仅有 index.js 文件
we're also including the formHandler js file,
还包含了 formHandler.js 文件
which means that webpack,
这意味着 webpack
saw that formHandler is now a dependency of the index.js file,
看到 formHandler 是 index.js 文件的依赖项
and it's added both of them to the main.js file,
将它们都添加到 main.js 文件中
so both form handler and index.js are part of our distributed main.js file.
所以 formHandler 和 index.js 都是分发文件 main.js 的一部分